Guide to the Branford College, Yale University, Records of the Master
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Branford College, Yale University, records of the master
1960-1973
RU 831
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.7
The records consist of administrative files maintained by the master of Branford College, Yale University, including correspondence, memoranda, lists, reports, and topical files.
Branford College (Yale University)
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 13-D-2 (YRG 13-D-2), Records of the master of Branford College.
Conditions Governing Access
Accessto the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative files maintained by the master of Branford College, Yale University, including correspondence, memoranda, lists, reports, and topical files.
Biographical / Historical
The title "Master" for chief executive officers of residential colleges was changed to "Head of College" in April of 2016.
Student housing; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Branford College (Yale University); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Student housing
- Records of the master, 1960-1962; Accession 19ND-A-411
  Arrangement
  The records are arranged in reverse chronological order by academic year.
  - 1961-1962
    - Activities (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
    - Allocations (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alumni (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Arts and Sciences (Yale Program) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Athletics (college) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Awards - Fellowships (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bills - Paid (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bills (Master's fund) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Branford College
      - Budget (Box 1, Folder 10 - 11)
      - Concert Series (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Council (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Dances (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Dean's Office (Box 1, Folder 15)
        General note
        See also: Accession 19ND-A-411, 1960-1962 Folder 182
      - Debating Team (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Dining Hall (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Directory (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Dramat (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Forums (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Freshman meeting (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Loan fund (student) (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Print Shop (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Repairs and Upkeep (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Shields (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Snack Bar (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Budget (University) (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Buildings, Pamphlet on Yale University, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Bursary
      - Office (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Staff
        See: Accession 19ND-A-411, 1960-1962 Folder 183 - 184
      - Correspondence
    - Calendars (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Campus Police Reports (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Caps and Gowns (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Chapel Committee (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Christmas Dinner 1961 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Class of
      - 1961 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - 1962 (Box 1, Folder 36 - 37)
      - 1963 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Comptroller's Office and Treasurer (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Counselors and Counselees, Sophomore Advisors (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Counseling and Placement (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Educational Research, Office of (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Fellows
      - Candidates, New (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - Junior (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - John Hay Fellow (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - Meetings and Agendas (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Freshman Dean's Office (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Health Department
    - Informal Discussion Courses
      - Senior (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - Sophomore (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Lists
    - Master's Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Military Service (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Mimeograph (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Other Colleges (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Parents' Day (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Personnel
    - President, Report to [empty folder] (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Provost's Office (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Punches (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Punches, Sports (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Purchasing (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Ramsey, Robert R., Jr. [empty folder] (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Reunion (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Room Letters - Ramsey, R.R., Jr. (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Room Inspection
    - Secretary's Office (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Senior Dinner (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Service Bureau (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Sheffield Scientific School (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Sophomore
      - Discussion Courses (Box 1, Folder 69)
      - Dinner (Box 1, Folder 70)
      - Evenings (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Storage Receipts (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Tower Bulletin (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Tuition, Fees, Expenses, etc. (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - University
      - Dining Halls (Box 1, Folder 75)
      - New Bureau [empty folder] (Box 1, Folder 76)
      - Post Office (Yale Station) (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Yale Volunteer Services (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Youth Welfare, Committee on [empty folder] (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - General Correspondence, by letter (Box 1, Folder 80)
      - B (Box 1, Folder 81)
      - C (Box 1, Folder 82)
      - D (Box 1, Folder 83)
      - F (Box 1, Folder 84)
      - G (Box 1, Folder 85)
      - H (Box 1, Folder 86)
      - J (Box 1, Folder 87)
      - K - L * M (Box 1, Folder 88)
      - N (Box 1, Folder 89)
      - O (Box 1, Folder 90)
      - P (Box 1, Folder 91)
      - Q R (Box 1, Folder 92)
      - S (Box 1, Folder 93)
      - T (Box 1, Folder 94)
      - W (Box 1, Folder 95)
      - X, Y, Z (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - 1960-1961
    - Allocations (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Alumni (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Athletics (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Bills - Paid (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Branford College
      - 1960-61 (Box 2, Folder 101)
      - Activities (Box 2, Folder 102 - 103)
      - Budgets (Box 2, Folder 104 - 105)
      - Concert Series (Box 2, Folder 106)
      - Council (Box 2, Folder 107)
      - Dean's Office (Box 2, Folder 108)
      - Dining Hall (Box 2, Folder 109)
      - Directory (Box 2, Folder 110)
      - Dramat (Box 2, Folder 111)
      - Forums (Box 2, Folder 112)
      - Loan fund (student) (Box 2, Folder 113)
      - Outing (Box 2, Folder 114)
      - Print Shop (Box 2, Folder 115)
      - Shields (Box 2, Folder 116)
      - Weekend (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Budget (University) (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Buffett-Punch (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Bursary
      - Bursary
        See: Accession 19ND-A-411, 1960-1962 Folder 190 - 191
      - Office (Box 2, Folder 120)
      - Staff
    - Calendars (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Campus Police Reports (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Caps and Gowns (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Caterers (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Christmas Dinner (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - Class of
      - 1961 (Box 2, Folder 126)
      - 1962 (Box 2, Folder 127)
      - 1963 (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - Coffee hour, 1960-61 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Commencement (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Comptroller's Office (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Counseling and Placement (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Faculty Offices (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Fellows
      - Candidates (Box 3, Folder 134)
      - Fund (Box 3, Folder 135)
      - John Hay Fellow (Box 3, Folder 136)
      - Meetings Agenda (Box 3, Folder 137)
      - Meetings and Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 138)
      - Sherries (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Freshmen Dean's Office (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Freshmen Meeting, Apr. 10, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Harvard Houses (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Health Department (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Hendrickson Lecture (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Hoyt Fellowship (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Informal Discussion Courses
      - Senior (Box 3, Folder 146)
      - Sophomore (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Masters (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Military Service (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Mimeograph (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Morse Fellowship (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Notices (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Other Colleges (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Parents Day (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - President, Report to (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Reunion, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - Room keys and inspection (Box 3, Folder 157)
    - Rooms, letters regarding (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - Scholarship (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - Senior Dinner and Cocktail Parties (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - Service Bureau (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - Sophomore Dinner (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - Sophomore Evenings (Box 3, Folder 163)
    - Storage, 1960-61 (Box 3, Folder 164)
    - Toll Calling, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - Tower Bulletin (Box 3, Folder 166)
    - University
      - Dining Halls (Box 3, Folder 167)
      - Post Office (Box 3, Folder 168)
    - General Correspondence
      - A (Box 3, Folder 169)
      - B (Box 3, Folder 170)
      - C (Box 3, Folder 171)
      - E (Box 3, Folder 172)
      - G (Box 3, Folder 173)
      - H (Box 3, Folder 174)
      - I (Box 3, Folder 175)
      - K (Box 3, Folder 176)
      - L (Box 3, Folder 177)
      - M (Box 3, Folder 178)
      - P (Box 3, Folder 179)
      - S (Box 3, Folder 180)
      - X, Y, Z (Box 3, Folder 181)
  - Restricted files (open; January 1, 2048)
    - 1962
      - Dean's Office (Box 4, Folder 182)
      - Bursary (Box 4, Folder 183 - 184)
      - Campus Police reports (Box 4, Folder 185)
      - Health department (Box 4, Folder 186)
      - Lists (Box 4, Folder 187)
      - Personnel (Box 4, Folder 188)
    - 1961
      - Room inspection (Box 4, Folder 189)
      - Bursary (Box 4, Folder 190 - 191)
      - Campus Police reports (Box 4, Folder 192)
- Records of the master, 1966-1973; Accession 2013-A-034
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until January 1, 2048
  - Police reports, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Incident reports-Memorial Chapel disturbance, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)